Guide to the Warner Cable Reston videotape collection, 1971-1997
George Mason University Libraries
Special Collections and Archives, George Mason University
Warner Cable Reston videotape collection
1971-1997
George Mason University. Special Collections and Archives.
Warner Cable Communications
C0139
9.25 linear feet (19 boxes)
The collection is comprised of programming generated by Warner Cable Communications regarding Reston, Virginia, and aired on the Warner Cable Community Access Channel. Some of these productions were made under contract with various groups, such as Reston Association, Reston Homeowners Association, and Reston Players.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Donated by Warner Cable Communications of Reston, Virginia, in June of 1989.
Historical Information
Reston is a planned community in Northern Virginia. Robert E. Simon, Jr. was the founder of Reston, he purchased the land with the proceeds from the sale of Carnegie Hall in New York City in 1961. Cable came to Reston in the 1970s and featured 14 channels, the local Washington and Baltimore channels and a channel or two devoted to local weather and community programming. From the mid-70s through the mid-90s, the system was owned by Warner Cable (and, for a while, under the Warner-Amex name). Under Warner, the system capacity was expanded to 80 channels.
Scope and Content
The collection is comprised of programming generated by Warner Cable Communications regarding Reston, Virginia, and aired on the Warner Cable Community Access Channel. Some of these productions were made under contract with various groups, such as Reston Association, Reston Homeowners Association, and Reston Players.
Series one is the only series in this small collection. The series includes a variety of different programs that were recorded onto 3/4 videotape cassettes. Some of the programs include, Reston Association elections and meetings. Others contain special programs about Reston, such as "A Place Called Reston" that aired in 1979.
Arrangement
Organized into one series.
Series 1: Reston Television, 1971-1997 (Boxes 1-19)
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
The Special Collections and Archives also holds the Planned Community Archives and other personal papers and organizational records that document Reston, Virginia and other planned communities.
Index Terms
Corporate Names:
Reston Association.; Warner Cable Communications.
Geographical Names:
Reston (Va.).
Subjects:
Theater--Virginia--Reston.
Contents List
- Series 1: Reston Television, 1971-1997
  The videotape cassettes are recordings of various television programs that aired on Warner Cable in Reston, Virginia. Topics that are covered are Reston Association meetings and various shows put on by the Reston Repertory Theater.
  - A. Smith Bowman Interview, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    155
  - A. Smith Bowman Historical Photos, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - A. Smith Bowman Historical Photographs, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    156
  - A. Smith Bowman, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - A. Smith Bowman, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Bertie Poston Outside Walking, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - "Country Music from the Country" National Folk Festival at Wolf Trap, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    157
  - Dateline Reston-Governance for Reston (Part 1), 1988 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    162
  - Election 1985, the Delegate Debate Plum vs. Thoburn (Box 2, Folder 3)
    159
  - Election 1987 Pennino-Douglas Debate (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Election 1987 Pennino-Douglas Debate (Box 2, Folder 5)
    160
  - International Children's Festival at Wolf Trap, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    153
  - International Children's Festival at Wolf Trap Farm Park, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Music is Medicine, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Reston Association Candidates Forum (Part 1), 1988 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Reston Association Meeting (Part 3), 1988 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Reston Association Meeting (Part 4), 1988 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Reston Community Association (RCA) (no. 1), 1988 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    161
  - Reston Community Association (RCA) (no. 2), 1988 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Reston Community Association (RCA) Meeting Special with Reston Land (Part 1), 1988 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Reston Community Association (RCA) Meeting Special with Reston Land (Part 2), 1988 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Reston Community Association(RCA) Meeting Special with Reston Land (Part 3), 1988 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Reston Community Center Dedication, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    154
    2 copies available on VHS. DVD copy available.
  - Reston Community Center Dedication, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Reston Governance Forum (Part 1), 1988 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Reston Governance Forum (Part 2), 1988 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Reston Governance Forum (Part 3), 1988 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Reston Repertory TV "A Place Called Reston", 1978-1979 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    Available on DVD.
  - Reston Repertory TV "A Place Called Reston", 1979 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Reston Repertory TV "A Place Called Reston" (no. 2), 1979 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Reston Repertory TV "A Place Called Reston" (no. 1), 1978-1979 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Reston Repertory TV "A Place Called Reston" (no. 2), 1979 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Reston Repertory TV "A Place Called Reston", 1979 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Reston Repertory Theater "In a Land That's Not Yours" by Bruce Zortman (Part 1), 1980 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Reston Repertory Theater "In a Land That's Not Yours" by Bruce Zortman (Part 2), 1980 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Reston Repertory Theater "In a Land That's Not Yours" by Bruce Zortman (Part 3), 1980 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Reston Repertory Theater "In a Land That is Not Yours" by Bruce Zortman (Part 1), 1980 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Reston Repertory Theater "In a Land That is Not Yours" by Bruce Zortman (Part 2), 1980 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Reston Repertory TV "Patterns" (Part 1) copy, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Reston Repertory TV "Patterns" (Part 2) copy, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Reston Repertory TV "Patterns" (Part 3) edited closing credits, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Reston Repertory TV "Patterns" (Part 1) copy, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Reston Repertory TV "Patterns" (Part 2) copy, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Reston Repertory TV "Patterns" (Part 3) Edited Closing Credits, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Reston Repertory TV "Pinnacles" Act I, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Reston Repertory TV "Pinnacles" Act II, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Reston Repertory TV "Pinnacles" Act III, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Reston Repertory "The Prodigal" (Part 1) Edit Master, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    158
  - Reston Repertory "The Prodigal" (Part 2) Edit Master, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Reston Repertory "The Prodigal" Re-Edit (Part 1), 1987 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Reston Repertory "The Prodigal" Re-Edit (Part 2), 1987 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Reston Repertory "The Prodigal" Re-Edit (Part 3), 1987 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Reston Repertory Television "Rape of Maria Perez" (Part 1) Edit Master, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Reston Repertory Theater "Rape of Maria Perez" (Part 2), 1981 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Reston Repertory Theater "Rape of Maria Perez" (Part 2) Re-Edit Master, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Reston Repertory "Rape of Maria Perez", 1982 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Reston Repertory "The Apprentice" by Sharon Loheu, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Reston Repertory "The Apprentice" by Sharon Cohen, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Reston Repertory Theater "The Stronger" by Strindberg, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Reston Repertory Theater "The Stronger" by Strindberg, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Reston Repertory "Tomorrow, and the day after, and the day after that", 1970s (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Reston Repertory "Tomorrow, and the day after, and the day after that", 1970s (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Reston Symposium-Keynote Address "Reston and the American Dream" by Dorn C. McGrath, Jr., 1985 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    31
  - Reston Symposium-Conference Address "New Towns in Perspective" by Paul D. Spreiregen (Part 1 of 2), 1985 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Reston Symposium-Conference Address "New Towns in Perspective" by Paul D. Spreiregen (Part 2 of 2), 1985 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Reston Symposium-Welcome and Orientation, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Reston Symposium-Plenary Session I (Part 1)-"Reston: New Town or Suburb?", 1985 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    32
  - Reston Symposium-Plenary Session I (Part 2)-"Reston: New Town or Suburb?", 1985 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Reston Symposium-Plenary Session II (Part 1)-"The Inclusive Community: Housing and Population Diversity", 1985 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Reston Symposium-Plenary Session II (Part 2)-"The Inclusive Community: Housing and Population Diversity", 1985 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Reston Symposium-Plenary Session III (Part 1)-"The Planned Environment: Structural and Natural Beauty", 1985 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Reston Symposium-Plenary Session III (Part 2)-"The Planned Environment: Structural and Natural Beauty", 1985 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Reston Symposium-Plenary Session IV (Part 1)-"Community Institutions and Governance", 1985 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Reston Symposium-Plenary Session IV (Part 2)-"Community Institutions and Governance", 1985 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Reston Symposium-Plenary Session IV (Part 3)-"Community Institutions and Governance", 1985 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    33
  - Reston Symposium-Plenary Session V (Part 1)-"Will It Sell?", 1985 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Reston Symposium-Plenary Session V (Part 2)-"Will It Sell?", 1985 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Reston Symposium-Plenary Session VI (Part 1)-"The Good Life: Cultural Educational and Recreational Opportunities", 1985 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Reston Symposium-Plenary Session VI (Part 2)-"The Good Life: Cultural, Educational and Recreational Opportunities", 1985 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Reston Symposium-Plenary Session VII (Part 1)-"Village and Town Centers: Shopping Centers or Urban Places?", 1985 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Reston Symposium-Plenary Session VII (Part 2)-"Village and Town Centers: Shopping Centers or Urban Places?"", 1985 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    34
  - Reston Symposium-Plenary Session VII (Part 3)-"Village and Town Centers: Shopping Centers or Urban Places?", 1985 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Reston Symposium-Plenary Session VIII (Part 1)-"Final Workshop Reports and Consensus", 1985 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Reston Symposium-Plenary Session VIII (Part 2)-"Final Workshop Reports and Consensus", 1985 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Reston Symposium-Robert Simon Speech (Part 1), 1985 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    Available on digital format.
  - Reston Symposium-Robert Simon Speech (Part 2), 1985 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Reston Town Center-Ground breaking (Part 1), 1988 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Reston Town Center Ground breaking (Part 2), 1988 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Reston Town Center Ground breaking (Part 3), 1988 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Reston Town Center Ground breaking Edited, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Reston Town Meeting-Reston Association Board (Part 3), 1988 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Reston Town Meeting-Reston Association Board (Part 1 of 2), 1988 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    163
  - Reston Town Meeting-Reston Association Board (Part 2 of 2), 1988 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Reston Town Meeting-Reston Association Board Meeting (Part 1), 1989 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Reston Town Meeting-Reston Association Board Meeting (Part 2), 1989 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Reston Town Meeting-Reston Association Board Meeting (Part 3), 1989 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Reston Town Meeting-Reston Association Candidate Forum (Part 1 of 2), 1989 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Reston Town Meeting-Reston Association Board Meeting (Part 2 of 2), 1989 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    164
  - Reston Town Meeting-Reston Association Board (Part 1), 1989 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Reston Town Meeting-Reston Association Board (Part 2), 1989 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Reston Town Meeting-Reston Association (Part 1), 1989 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Reston Town Meeting-Reston Association (Part 2), 1989 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Reston Town Meeting-Reston Association (Part 3), 1989 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Reston Visitors Center Dedication, 1982 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Reston Visitors Center Dedication (no. 2), 1982 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Seniors "Tom Currier" (1st half) and "Nancy Echols" (2nd half), 1982 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Songs of Gospel-National Folk Festival, 1981 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Special-Jesse Jackson "I am Somebody" (Edit Master), 1986 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - "Tom Currier" as featured on "Seniors", 1982 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Reston Citizens Association Board Meeting, January 1996 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    Available on VHS.
  - Reston Citizens Association Board Meeting, February 26, 1996 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Reston Citizens Association Board Meeting, March 1996 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Reston Citizens Association Board Meeting, January 27, 1997 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Reston Citizens Association Board Meeting, February 24, 1997 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Reston Citizens Association Board Meeting, April 21, 1997 (Box 19, Folder 7)